[roars]
[narrator]
Strange beasts
and monsters.
[squeaking]
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
The mysterious unknown.
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words...
are called...
Hunters.
[Satotz] With no further ado,
the Hunter Exam will now begin.
I am Satotz, your Examiner
for the First Phase of the Exam.
It's my responsibility to lead you all
to the Second Phase.
The First Phase is already underway.
HOPE x AND x AMBITION
[narrator] It's been two hours
since the Exam began,
and the applicants have traveled
more than 30 kilometers
from the starting line.
No one knows how far they'll have to go.
Nevertheless,
they struggle to match the leader's pace.
It is a monotonous course
with no end in sight
and applicants have already started
to drop out.
[panting]
[Nicholas]
Extrapolated from historical data,
it's safe to assume
this will be a 40-kilometer course.
And if my calculations are correct,
we should be nearing the end.
[pants loudly]
[Leorio]
What the hell was I thinking?
You've got to be a monster
to pass the Hunter Exam
and I'm surrounded by them.
-[yelling] Hey, wait up, kid.
-[Killua] Hm?
How about you show
a little respect for the Exam.
What do you mean?
I mean quit using a damn skateboard.
That's cheating.
-How's that?
-How?
This is an endurance test,
that's how.
-[Gon] No, it's not!
-Huh?
What are you babbling about now, Gon?
The examiner guy only said
we had to follow him.
Hey, whose side are you on, anyway?
-[Killua] Hey, how old are you?
-Twelve years old.
[Killua] Same as me.
I think I'll run for a little while.
Cool!
[laughs]
-My name's Killua.
-Hi, I'm Gon!
[Leorio] Damn kids!
You're not going to make a fool out of me.
[labored breathing]
[Nicholas]
Impossible. Simply impossible.
My calculations are never wrong.
What's happening?
Am I actually going to fail?
Me? Fail?
No, that's preposterous!
[yelling] I won't accept that.
I won't!
[Nicolas, groaning, gasping for air]
[Amori]
Hey, rookie!
[laughs]
Damn, you're a real mess.
I don't think I've ever seen anyone
run out of steam this early.
[Amori] Yeah, he's right.
You must really be pathetic.
[Umori] You think someone like you has got
what it takes to pass the Hunter Exam?
[Imori]
Don't ever come back, loser.
[crying out]
[screams]
[Tonpa]
Here.
Thanks for your help.
Great job, guys.
He won't be recovering from that
anytime soon, I can promise you.
And I bet you he won't be applying
for the Exam again, either.
I've really got to hand it to you
you sure do love crushing rookies,
don't you, Tonpa.
[Tonpa snickers]
It's the only reason I get out of bed
in the morning.
[music plays]
[Kurapika] It's been about four hours
since the First Phase began
and we've run at least 60 kilometers.
How much farther do we need to go?
[panting heavily]
[Leorio]
Rookies almost never pass a Hunter Exam.
Just one every three years or so.
I'm just a regular guy.
I don't stand a chance.
What the hell was I thinking?
Damn it.
-[briefcase thuds]
-[Gon grunts]
[panting]
Hey, forget about him.
You've got to keep moving.
[yelling]
Man, screw this!
I'm becoming a Hunter,
no matter what!
Damn it all!
[snickers]
-[grunts] Got it.
-[Killua gasps]
That was awesome!
[laughs]
[Killua]
Can I try that later?
[Gon] Sure, if I can try your skateboard.
[Satotz]
We've reached the 80-kilometer mark.
Now, let's pick up the pace a bit,
shall we?
[heavy panting]
-He can't be serious!
-He's insane.
Look at him prance up those stairs,
like it's no big deal.
He's not even out of breath.
[Geretta] If he doesn't ease up,
people are going to start dropping
like flies.
Hey, I've got an idea. Let's race
to the finish, see who's faster.
[Gon] Sure, okay.
But the loser has to buy dinner.
[Killua]
Yeah, you're on.
[both] Ready, go!
[grunting loudly]
[Kurapika]
Are you okay, Leorio?
Great. I've never been better.
If I forget how stupid I look,
it's a whole lot easier to keep going.
[yells]
[Kurapika laughs]
I suppose I should probably follow suit.
Leorio, I have a question for you.
What's up? First Phase too easy for you,
so you've got to make it harder?
Save your breath, Kurapika.
You're going to need it.
Why do you want to be a Hunter?
Is it really just about the money?
It can't be.
We haven't known each other very long,
but that's not like you.
I mean, sure, your attitude is terrible
and you aren't too bright, either.
[Leorio grumbles]
But I know,
shallowness isn't among your downfalls.
I've known many people whose only passion
in life was money.
And I can tell you're nothing like them.
[Leorio]
You've got it all figured out, don't you?
-The Scarlet Eyes.
-[Leorio] Huh?
That's why the Kurta Clan was targeted.
Scarlet Eyes are a special trait
possessed only by the Kurta.
When our emotions are heightened,
the color of our eyes will change,
taking on a shade of scarlet.
In that state, the color of our eyes
is considered one of the seven most
beautiful colors in the world
and they command a hefty price
on the black market.
[Leorio] So, that's why
the Phantom Troupe attacked you?
Your eyes?
They plucked the eyes
from each of my brethren's corpses.
Not a single one escaped desecration.
Even now I can hear them,
the anguished screams
of their darkened eyes.
I swear on my life
that I will capture the Phantom Troupe.
Once I do, I'll avenge my clan
by taking back their eyes.
[Leorio] That's why you want to be
a Hunter?
[Kurapika] That's right.
If I become a contract Hunter
with wealthy clientele,
I'll have access
to black market information.
But you'll have to be
the kind of Hunter you hate.
You think you'll be able to swallow
your pride when you need to?
The blow to my pride is nothing.
Not when compared to my clan's suffering.
[Leorio]
Well, sorry.
I don't have some big noble cause
like you do.
The only thing I'm after
is money.
That's not true.
-Of course it is.
-It's not.
Be honest. Do you really believe that
money can buy everything? Tell the truth.
Damn right, I do.
For the right price,
you can buy treasures,
dreams, hearts,
and even people's lives.
Take that back, Leorio.
I will not stand here
and allow you to insult the Kurta.
Why?
It's the truth, isn't it.
If I had money,
my friend would still be alive today!
Was he ill?
Yeah. It was a curable disease.
The problem was that the operation
cost a fortune.
I was naive.
I figured I could become a doctor
so I could cure kids
with the same disease.
And tell their parents
they owed me nothing.
It was free of charge.
That was my dream.
A pretty good joke, right?
Turns out, to become a doctor
you already have to have
an obscene amount of money.
Get it now?
The whole world runs on money.
So I'm going to get
as much as I can.
See you at the finish line.
Catch you later, old man.
Hey, I'm not old.
Can't you tell I'm a teenager
just like you?
[Gon]
Huh? No way!
HUNTER GLOSSARY
KILLUA
[panting]
I can't go on.
This... this is it,
I'm finished.
[panting]
I've got to tell you, Gon.
I'm pretty impressed
that you can keep up with me.
You are?
[laughs]
Or maybe they're all so slow,
you just seem fast.
Man, I thought the Hunter Exam
was going to be more of a challenge.
This is boring.
[Gon] Hey, why do you want to be
a Hunter, anyway?
Who me?
-I never said I wanted to be a Hunter.
-Huh?
I just heard that the Exam
was supposed to be really hard.
It sounded kind of fun
so here I am.
But it's not as fun as I thought.
[Killua]
What about you?
[Gon] Well, the thing is,
my dad's a Hunter.
So, I decided I was going to be
a Hunter just like him, no matter what.
[Killua]
Hm, so what kind of Hunter is he?
[Gon] No idea.
[laughs]
-It's the weirdest thing I've ever heard.
-Huh?
You wanna be the same kind of Hunter
as your dad
but you don't know anything
about him? That's nuts.
Mito's the one who raised me.
and she told me a little,
but I've only ever seen him in pictures
she showed me from a long time ago.
-Wait, so who's Mito?
-She's my aunt.
She said that my dad took the Hunter Exam
when he was only 12 years old, too.
He passed his first try
and became a Hunter.
That's when he decided
to leave the island.
So, I came here in order to find out
why he chose being a Hunter
over staying at home with me.
[man]
The exit! Oh, thank goodness.
[man two] We're finally getting out
of this dark tunnel.
Now then. Let's see how many applicants
have made it this far.
[both] Goal!
[laughing]
Yeah, I did it!
I finished first.
What are you talking about?
I totally won.
-[Gon] No, I won.
-[Killua] I won.
[Gon] I was faster than you,
so you have to buy me dinner.
[Killua] No way.
I was faster so you're buying me dinner.
[Gon]
Na-ah, I was faster.
Hey, which one of us was fastest?
You crossed the finish line
simultaneously.
Okay.
Fine, I guess I'll have to buy
your dinner.
[Killua]
Huh?
But then you have to buy me
my dinner, okay?
I don't get it.
Hey, Mr. Satotz,
is this where the Second Phase begins?
No, it isn't.
We have quite a way to go.
[Gon] Oh, man!
[heavy breathing]
[Leorio groans, laughs]
[Gon] Hey, Kurapika!
Hey.
Is this our destination?
Nope, not yet.
Hm, I see.
-Looks like the fog is lifting.
-Ah, really?
Whoa!
[Satotz] The Milsy Wetlands,
also known as Swindler's Swamp.
We must cross it to reach
Phase Two of the Exam.
This place is home to
a variety of truly bizarre animals,
many of which are
crafty, voracious creatures
who deceive and feast
on human prey.
So please, be very careful.
If you're deceived,
you'll surely die.
[clamoring]
[creaking]
[grunting]
[yells] Wait for me!
These wetland creatures
are not to be underestimated,
for they will use every trick in the book
to fool their prey.
[gasping]
This is an ecosystem
in which all creatures hunt
by the art of deception.
And that is why it's also known
as Swindler's Swamp.
Now then, please follow me closely
so you won't be deceived.
[scoffs]
Is he messing with us?
If we know they'll try to deceive us,
who's gonna fall for it?
[man]
Don't fall for it!
Listen, didn't I just say
that we won't?
[groans]
Don't let them fool you!
[surprised gasping]
He's lying.
That man is lying to you.
He's an impostor!
A total fraud.
I'm the real Examiner,
you got it?
Impostor? What's going on here?
But then, who is he, really?
I'll prove it, look at this!
[clamoring]
Oh wow, he looks like Mr. Satotz!
This is a man-faced ape
from the Milsy Wetlands.
A man-faced what?
The man-faced ape loves the taste
of human flesh.
But their limbs are really long
and thin, so they're actually quite weak.
That's why they disguise themselves
as humans.
They trick us into following them
into the wetlands,
where they work together with other
creatures to kill and eat us.
That's what he wants. To deceive
the entire Hunter applicant pool
and feast on every one of you.
Bastard.
Oh yeah?
Well, then that would certainly explain
why he doesn't walk like a normal human.
What?
-[cards flutter]
-[everyone gasps]
[laughs]
I see, I see.
That settles it, then.
So you are the real one.
[music plays]
[Hanzo] Hold on, he's the real Examiner?
[screeching]
The Examiners are Hunters.
Each is hand-picked by the Exam Committee
to do this job without pay.
Anyone who holds the title
we're vying for ourselves
could have deflected that attack.
And quite easily, I might add.
I shall take that as a compliment.
Thank you.
Still, should you choose to attack me
again, for any reason,
I will have no choice but to report you
for attacking an Examiner,
and have you immediately disqualified.
-Is that clear?
-Of course.
[cawing]
Nature can be so brutal.
It's hard to watch.
So he was a man-faced ape as well.
He was trying to confuse the applicants
and lure some of you away.
These attempts are to be expected.
-We can't let our guard down.
-Right.
Please be aware
that you will encounter such deceptions
on a regular basis.
I must assume that
a number of you were fooled
into suspecting my true identity
Oh, well, I uh...
[chuckles, embarrassed]
Understand,
I want to make it abundantly clear
that if any of you are to lose sight of me
once we enter the fog
of the Milsy Wetlands,
you have no hope whatsoever
of reaching the Second Phase of the Exam.
You've been warned.
Now, let's begin.
Please follow me.
Oh, great.
It's another marathon.
Except this time
we're in a swamp
and running on wet ground requires
significantly more energy.
[narrator] The applicants have finally
left the long, dark tunnel
and stepped into the light.
So far, 36 candidates have
withdrawn from the Exam,
and 368 remain.
Their next challenge will be
the Milsy Wetlands,
which is also known as
Swindler's Swamp.
The excruciating Hunter Exam
continues.
[Gon] Next time.
"Hisoka x Is x Sneaky."
Okie-dokie!